Previously on "Transformers Prime..."
在上一集中
Assembly of the Omega Lock is entering the final stage.
终极之锁的组装已进入最终阶段
Megatron is preparing to cyber-form Earth.
威震天正准备把地球数字化
Autobots, lock on to those coordinates.
汽车人 锁定坐标
Spectrum analysis confirms
频谱分析确认
that the Synthetic Energon is stable.
合成能量已经稳定
But pity you won't live long enough to witness the fruits of your labor.
可惜你无法眼看着自己的研究成果开枝散叶
Your high and mighty leader wanted your Predacons exterminated!
是你那高高在上的首领 想要除掉你们巨狰狞
And my only mistake was not seeing the extermination through.
而我唯一的错误就是没有斩草除根
You should have faced me as a beast!
你应该在我面前保持野兽形态
Globalize what remains of our forces.
动用所有剩余力量！
This will be our last stand.
在此与他决一死战！
The Omega Lock's control station is located on the lower deck.
终极之锁的控制台在底层甲板
Come on!
快！
I am making my way there now.
我正往那儿赶
Copy, Ratchet.
收到 救护车
We will rendezvous at the objective.
我们在目标处汇合
R.C., lead stealth team to secure the Omega Lock.
阿尔茜 带领突击小队夺取终极之锁
Ultra Magnus, you and the Wreckers storm the bridge.
通天晓 你带雷霆救援队突袭舰桥
Prevent the Decepticons from targeting the device
不能让霸天虎锁定设备目标
if stealth team is delayed.
一旦突击小队被拖住
Optimus, if we fail to secure the lock before it's ready to deploy,
擎天柱 万一没能在终极之锁启动前把它抢下来
do we destroy it?
要不要把它摧毁？
I do not intend to squander a second chance to restore Cybertron.
我不打算再次浪费复苏塞博特恩的机会
Wreckers.
雷霆救援队！
Bee, Smokescreen... with me.
小蜂 烟幕 跟我来
Smokescreen!
烟幕！
Raaaah!
啊！
Go on without me.
你们先去
That isn't the mission.
你要开小差吗？
There's something I need to do.
我得先去做件事
Shut it down, Shockwave.
关掉它 震荡波
I cannot allow you to harm Earth.
我决不允许你危害地球！
The planet will not be harmed...
这个星球不会受到伤害
only its indigenous life-forms.
毁灭的只不过是本地的物种
Over my sparkless husk.
除非你跨过我的尸体！
Aaah!
啊！
Ratchet, we're approaching your position.
救护车 我们正接近你的位置
What?!
什么？
Scrap.
该死！
Attack!
进攻！
Pack light. Pack light.
轻装上阵 轻装上阵
Pack smart.
重质不重量
I was hoping you'd still be here.
幸好你还在这儿
Secure the bridge!
夺取舰桥！
Ultra Magnus to all units. We will be delayed.
通天晓呼叫所有单位 我们要迟到了
Soundwave pulled one of his relocation tricks.
声波又玩儿了一次传送的花招
Raf, can you get me onto the warship's bridge?
拉夫 能把我弄到战舰的舰桥上吗？
Sure, now that I have a fix on it.
当然能 我已经掌握了它的坐标
But you won't have a chance against Soundwave.
但你怎么可能敌得过声波？！
I will if I have backup.
有后援就行
Eh... ah!
呃啊!
Lord Megatron, the Omega Lock is fueled and ready.
威震天陛下 终极之锁充能完毕 准备就绪
Shockwave, commence Omega Lock firing sequence.
震荡波 启动终极之锁发射程序
Eh! Oh, scrap!
什么？噢 该死！
Surprise!
没想到吧！
Hah!
喝！
Pick on someone your own size.
别以大欺小啊！
Raf, showtime!
拉夫 好戏该开始了！
Are you sure about this, Jack?
真的要这样吗 杰克？
Last time you crossed the streams...
上次能量流重叠…
Do it, Raf... now!
动手 拉夫 快！
Enjoy the shadow zone, dude.
好好享受暗影空间吧 老兄
Come on. We need to figure out how to navigate this thing.
快 得弄明白怎么驾驶这个大家伙
Shockwave, prepare to fire the...
震荡波 准备发射…
What?!
什么？
Whoa!
喔哇！
Dude, where'd you learn to drive?
伙计 你是哪个驾校的？！
Special delivery.
快递到了！
That way, right?
那边 对吧？
Optimus! Catch!
擎天柱 接着！
Smokescreen!
烟幕！
Optimus, you must use the Saber to destroy the Omega Lock.
擎天柱 你必须用星辰剑毁掉终极之锁！
It is the onty way to save Earth!
这是拯救地球的唯一办法！
The Star Saber!
星辰剑！
No!
不！
Prepare to join your scout in the Allspark.
跟你的侦察兵一起回归火种源吧！
Megatron!
威震天！
You took my voice.
你夺走了我的声音！
You will never rob anyone of anything ever again.
可你休想再夺走任何人的任何东西！
Lord Megatron! No!
威震天陛下 不！
I will avenge you, master!
我要替你报仇 主人！
Starscream! Do not be a fool!
红蜘蛛 别傻了！
Curse you and your logic!
现在你还扯什么该死的逻辑！
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂
Your voice...
你的声音…
My voice? What are you...
我的声音 你说什么…
my voice!
我的声音！
Ratchet, I have my pipes back!
救护车 我的发声器回来了！
The cyber matter...
是塞博特恩网状物
It is the only possible explanation.
这是唯一合理的解释
It would seem the old field medic made good after all.
看来曾经的战地医生终于兑现承诺了
Optimus Prime to all units.
擎天柱呼叫所有单位 威震天已不复存在
Yes!
太棒了！
Hooah!
- 呜哇！ - 雷霆救援队 夺取舰桥的任务完成得非常出色
It wasn't us, sir.
并非我们所为 长官
The credit belongs to the humans.
都是人类的功劳
Hoo-Yeah!
哦耶！
The Omega Lock is under our control.
终极之锁掌握在我们手中
I propose that we put it to good use.
我建议物尽其用
Agreed, old friend.
我同意 老朋友
Ultra Magnus, set course for Cybertron.
通天晓 设定航向 飞往塞博特恩
Hey, Raf, if you could tear yourself away from your laptop for two seconds...
嘿 拉夫 跟你的笔记本小别几秒钟
grid yourself up here so we can get to Cybertron already.
把自己传送过来 咱们一起去塞博特恩吧
Wait. Who's that?
等等 那是谁？
Bee?
小蜂？
Eh... ah. Your elbow articulator is digging into my lateral flexor!
呃啊 你的胳膊肘快捅进我的腰里了！
Do you intend to whine for the duration of the voyage?
你打算一路都这样抱怨下去么？
Optimus, I... was never able to learn
擎天柱 我…一直都没参透
Shockwave's side of the cyber matter equation.
震荡波对于网状物的研究
This may be all we ever have.
我们可能只有这些了
And Cybertron is a much larger planet than Earth.
而塞博特恩要比地球大得多
Then we must launch the cyber matter at Cybertron's very core.
那么我们必须将网状物注入塞博特恩的核心
Into the heart of Primus himself?
注入原始天尊的心脏？
Commander, we've arrived at the Well of all Sparks.
指挥官 我们已经抵达火种源之井
Ahh. Such luster.
啊 多美的光辉啊！
What? I'm joining the winning team.
怎么了 我本来就是墙头草嘛！
Aaah!
呀啊！
The Predacon.
是那只巨狰狞
Though our home world is once again capable of supporting life...
尽管家园重获了维持生命的能力
we have much rebuilding to do.
但我们仍有很多重建工作要做
Alas, we will miss our home away from home
也罢 我们会怀念远方这个家园的
and the family we've made here.
还有这里的亲人
If 'Cons are still out there, won't Earth be on their radar?
逍遥法外的虎子 不会再打地球的主意吗？
Raf, if you ever need me, need us for any reason,
拉夫 只要你们需要我 需要我们做任何事情
we're just a space bridge away.
我们就在太空桥的另一头
Besides, we'll be in good hands with
而且 我们会得到妥善照顾 你 杰克和神子 将继续为E部门效力
In our semi-Official capacity.
就算是半官方身份
Whoa! We are Agents?!
哇喔 我们是探员了？
Consultants.
是顾问
Until you're of age.
直到年龄符合要求
I trust that Unit-E doesn't have any rules
我相信E部门不会食古不化
forbidding the enlistment of rusty, old Autobot consultants?
拒绝招募一个老掉牙的汽车人顾问吧？
Ratchet? You of all...
救护车 你竟然…
Yep, yep, yep.
没错没错！
I know where I am needed.
我知道自己的价值所在
Raf...
拉夫…
I know, Bee.
我明白 小蜂
You don't need to say anything.
什么都不用说
I never did.
以前我也没说过
Miko, I guess this is...
神子 我觉得现在…
It's been quite a ride.
这段旅途我永生难忘
Keep in touch, Jack.
保持联络 杰克
Don't make me hunt you down.
别逼我回来追你
Until we meet again, old friend.
来日再会 老朋友